Ayushi Shakya

(+65) 90370392 | ayushi.s.2023@mitb.smu.edu.sg | LinkedIn | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Data-oriented Risk management professional with ~7 years of experience specializing in operational risk analytics and control monitoring across global organizations. Recent master's in data science graduate from Singapore Management University. 6 years of experience in on-site stakeholder management successfully driving data literacy and analytics adoption across telecom, manufacturing, healthcare, q-commerce and financial services clients for proactive risk management

EXPERIENCE

COMMERCIAL DATA ANALYST

Singapore

foodpanda

Dec 2023 - Jun 2024

- Architected end-to-end data pipelines using Google BigQuery to track key commercial metrics, enabling selfservice analytics for stakeholders across business functions
- Improved restaurants monitoring through deep-dive analytics projects, developing key performance metrics, and providing insights to drive critical operational decisions

SENIOR ASSOCIATE RISK ANALYTICS

Bengaluru, India

Grant Thornton LLP (US)

Jun 2022 - Jul 2023

- Architected analytics-based risk assessment pertaining to Payroll, Travel & Expense, and Journal Entry analytics; identified and articulated key trends and insights for non-technical client audiences using Power BI
- Tested operating effectiveness of IT controls against the benchmarked standards of SOX for a leading financial services company
- Conceptualized and Developed Go-to Market solutions pertaining to Risk Analytics; the demo materials contributed to winning 2 new clients for the firm

BUSINESS CONSULTANT

Gurugram, India

ΕY

Jun 2017 - May 2022

- Headed a team of 5 analysts for data-driven revenue assurance (RA), preventing USD 300K in revenue leakage; enabled the client's digital transformation by utilizing Apache Hive to test and validate logic, deploying optimized solutions on the inhouse RA tool to enhance monitoring for 20+ high and medium-risk controls
- Streamlined the framework to monitor Capex with ~90% accuracy for USD 309 Mn in installed assets across ~32k locations by reconciling the Fixed Assets Register with network deployment via reusable iterative algorithm in Alteryx
- Collaborated with internal IA teams, client business owners, and the corporate audit group to automate analytical scripts in Alteryx for 200+ controls across business functions
- Published dashboards of risk indicators in Power BI to help the client continuously monitor control effectiveness health
- Collaborated with the Corporate Audit Group to charter internal audit scopes by leveraging extensive data analytics through trends and metric analysis across various operational circles for 2 financial quarter reviews

ASSOCIATE CONSULTANT, ANALYST

ΕY

- Conducted end to end systems reconciliations for Enterprise Business Unit on-site in Cameroon, Africa to highlight
 operational, financial, and regulatory risks; assisted to rectify issues leading to uplift in monthly revenue by USD 125K
- Led on-ground Order-to-Cash process evaluation and re-design for Cameroon's biggest telecom Enterprise business
- Designed Risk and Control Matrix, KPI, and Exceptions Dashboards, and provided hands-on training to the telecom client's operations team to support Control Operationalization
- Streamlined and validated billing processes for a tower company, ensuring alignment with MSA contract provisions and accuracy in invoicing

EDUCATION

SINGAPORE MANAGEMENT UNIVERSITY

Masters in Data Science | MITB Scholarship

Singapore 2023 – 2024

JAYPEE INSTITUTE OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY

B.Engg Electronics & Communication | Training & Placement Cell coordinator

New Delhi, India 2013 – 2017

SKILLS

Functional: Data Analytics & Internal Audit (SOX, Revenue Assurance), Process Improvement/ Re-engineering (Internal Controls Monitoring), Machine Learning, Business Analytics, Metrics Reporting, Business Intelligence, Hypothesis (A/B) Testing, Data Visualization, Key performance indicators (KPIs), Objectives and key results (OKRs) Technical: Python, R, SAS-Viya, Alteryx, Power BI, Tableau, MySQL, Google BigQuery
Tools: Google Cloud Platform, SharePoint, MS Office, Excel, Visio, Subex ROC (Fraud Monitoring), RSA Archer (Internal Audit Documentation), Apache Hive